Guide to the Internet-First University Press collection, 1999-2013.
Internet-First University Press collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Internet-First University Press collection, 1999-2013.
6746
J. Robert, Cooke
1
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
DVDs and supplementary materials from Cornell University conferences, lectures, and presentations.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Internet-First University Press was the outcome of a project, "Creating an Open Access Paradigm for Scholarly Publishing," led by J. Robert Cooke and Kenneth M. King and funded by the Atlantic Philanthropies. The project created online and DVD versions of interviews, lectures, and symposia.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
DVDs and supplementary materials from Cornell University conferences, lectures, and presentations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cooke, J. Robert,; Bethe, Hans A. (Hans Albrecht), 1906-2005.; Bauer, Simon.; Cooke, W. Donald.; Hoffmann, Roald.; McLafferty, Fred W.; Scheraga, Harold A., 1921-; Foote, Robert H.; Corson, Dale R.; Marcham, Frederick George, 1898-1992.; Keeton, William T.; Spencer, James W.; Abrams, M. H. (Meyer Howard), 1912-2015.; Ware, Barlow.; Brutsaert, Wilfried, 1934-; Parlange, J.-Y. (Jean-Yves); Richardson, Robert C. (Robert Coleman) 1937-2013.; White, Richard N.; Abrams, M. H. (Meyer Howard), 1912-2015; Bauer, Simon; Bethe, Hans A. (Hans Albrecht), 1906-2005; Brutsaert, Wilfried, 1934-; Cooke, W. Donald; Corson, Dale R.; Foote, Robert H.; Hoffmann, Roald; Keeton, William T.; Marcham, Frederick George, 1898-1992; McLafferty, Fred W.; Parlange, J.-Y. (Jean-Yves); Richardson, Robert C. (Robert Coleman), 1937-2013; Scheraga, Harold A., 1921-; Spencer, James W.; Ware, Barlow; White, Richard N.; Cooke, J. Robert.; King, Kenneth M.; Furry, Ronald Bay, 1931-; Kirk, Mark.; LaFeber, Walter.; Nesheim, Malden C.; Hartmanis, Juris.; Murphy, Royse P. (Royse Peak), 1914-; Kass, Lee B., 1946-; Rehkugler, Gerald Edwin, 1935-; Christy, Ralph D.; Brown, Susan K.; Korf, Richard P.; Zaitlin, Milton,; Viands, Donald R.,; DiSalvo, Francis J.; Abruña, Héctor D.,; Rhodes, Frank Harold Trevor.; Love, Harry H. (Harry Houser), 1880-1966.; Moon, F. C., 1939-; King, J. M. (John McKain), 1927-2016.; Scott, Norman R. (Norman Ross), 1918-; Freed, Jack H.; Crane, Brian.; Reisner, John Henry, 1888-; Sisler, Daniel G.; Call, David L., 1932-; Cornell University.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Department of Biological and Environmental Engineering.; Cornell University. School of Civil and Environmental Engineering.; Cornell University; Cornell University. School of Civil and Environmental Engineering; Internet-First University Press.; International Association for Computational Mechanics.; International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures.; Cornell University.; Cornell University.; Janus Conference on Research Library Collections
Subjects:
Open access publishing.; Internet publishing.; Student movements -- History. -- United States; Agriculture; Internet publishing; Open access publishing; Student movements
Places:
Nanking (China) -- Agriculture.; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Janus Conference on Research Library Collections: Managing the Shifting Ground Between Writers and Readers, 2005; DVD-182 (Box 1)
- Groundbreaking: Life Sciences Technology Building, 2005-05-11; DVD-178 (Box 1)
- The Legacy of Dale R. Corson: Papers, Photographs, and Videos, 2009; DVD-2380 (Box 1)
- Corson: Cornell Center for Material Research Luncheon, 2004-12-01; DVD-2381 (Box 1)
- A Conversation with Fred W. McLafferty, 2006; DVD-179 (Box 1)
- Remembering W. Donald Cooke: Department of Chemistry and Chemical Biology, 2007-11-10; DVD-185 (Box 1)
- A Conversation with Simon H. Bauer, 2006; DVD-175 (Box 1)
- A Conversation with W. Donald Cooke, 2006-04-14; DVD-177 (Box 1)
- The Internet-First University Press Archive 001, 2005-04-05; DVD-183 (Box 1)
- Remembering Hans Bethe: Conversations with Hans Bethe, 2005; DVD-174 (Box 1)
- Hans Bethe: Celebrating "An Exemplary Life", 2005-09-18; DVD-173 (Box 1)
- "Quantum Physics Made Relatively Simple," three lectures by Hans Bethe, CD-272 (Box 1)
- The Corson Symposium: Strategy for a Great Research University, 1999-12-06-1999-12-07; DVD-184 (Box 1)
- A Conversation with Roald Hoffmann, 2006; DVD-176 (Box 1)
- A Conversation with Harold A. Scheraga, 2006; DVD-180 (Box 1)
- Animal Reproduction: Reflections by Robert H. Foote, 2006; DVD-181 (Box 1)
- The Legacy of Frederick G. Marcham, 2006; DVD-172 (Box 1)
- "Final Project Report to the Atlantic Philanthropies" by J. Robert Cooke, Principal Investigator and Kenneth M. King, Project Director, 2006-08-01 (Box 1)
- Biological and Environmental Department History, 2007-06-14; DVD-2383 (Box 1)
- "A Pioneering Department: Evolution from Rural Engineering to Biological and Environmental Engineering at Cornell University, 1907-2007," by Ronald B. Furry, edited by John Marcham, with CD of volume, 2007 (Box 1)
- "In Their Own Voices: A Conversation with Howard W. Riley" (transcript of interview) (Box 1)
- "Riley-Robb Hall At Cornell University: Celebrating Its Opening," edited by J. Robert Cooke and Ronald B. Furry (Box 1)
- "The Case for a Primary Diplomatic Relationship with China," Mark Kirk, introduced by Professor Walter LaFeber, 2004-11-08; CD-273 (Box 1)
- Corson: Cornell Center for Material Research Luncheon, 2004-12-01; CD-274 (Box 1)
- Cornell 1969: Key Issues Then and Now. A University Faculty Forum, Kennedy Hall, 1999-05-03; DVD-196 (Box 1)
- "The 30th Anniversary of WSH Takeover" panel discussion, Memorial Room, Willard Straight Hall, 1999-04-19; DVD-195 (Box 1)
- "A World Without Disorder: Absolute Zero Temperature. A Robert Richardson Lecture, 1 Aug 1979," DVD with selected articles from the Cornell Chronicle about Cornell research on absolute zero and superconductivity, 2008; DVD-201 (Box 1)
- Conference Proceedings for Computation of Shell and Spatial Structures, the 6th Annual Conference of IASS-IACM (International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures - International Association for Computational Mechanics), held on the Cornell campus on 28-31 May 2008, Disc 1, 2008-05-28-2008-05-31; DVD-516 (Box 1)
- Conference Proceedings for Computation of Shell and Spatial Structures, the 6th Annual Conference of IASS-IACM (International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures - International Association for Computational Mechanics), held on the Cornell campus on 28-31 May 2008, Disc 2, 2008-05-28-2008-05-31; DVD-517 (Box 1)
- Conference Proceedings for Computation of Shell and Spatial Structures, the 6th Annual Conference of IASS-IACM (International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures - International Association for Computational Mechanics), held on the Cornell campus on 28-31 May 2008, Disc 3, 2008-05-28-2008-05-31; DVD-518 (Box 1)
- Conference Proceedings for Computation of Shell and Spatial Structures, the 6th Annual Conference of IASS-IACM (International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures - International Association for Computational Mechanics), held on the Cornell campus on 28-31 May 2008, Disc 4, 2008-05-28-2008-05-31; DVD-519 (Box 1)
- Conference Proceedings for Computation of Shell and Spatial Structures, the 6th Annual Conference of IASS-IACM (International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures - International Association for Computational Mechanics), held on the Cornell campus on 28-31 May 2008, Disc 5, 2008-05-28-2008-05-31; DVD-520 (Box 1)
- A Collection of Cornell Chronicle articles about James W. Spencer, 2009; CD-534 (Box 1)
- "The Legacy of Dale R. Corson," printed volume and DVD, 2009; DVD-708 (Box 1)
- M.H. Abrams at Cornell University printed, 2009 (Box 1)
- M.H. Abrams at Cornell University DVD, 2010; DVD-580 (Box 1)
- "The Division of Nutritional Sciences at Cornell University: A History and Personal Reflections," by Malden C. Nesheim, 2010 (Box 1)
- Richard Norman White: DVD includes his CV, the statement for the annual university faculty memorial booklet, and a video recording of the memorial gathering held on May 1, 2010, School of Civil and Environmental Engineering., 2010-05-01; DVD-695 (Box 1)
- "The Origin and History of the Internet: A Lecture by Kenneth M. King." CAPE lecture, 2011; DVD-711 (Box 1)
- "Evolution of Plant Breeding at Cornell University: A Centennial History, 1907-2006," by Royse P. Murphy with Lee B. Kass (book), 2011 (Box 1)
- The Evolution of Plow Design: The Supplemental Resources of the CD-ROM, 2011 (Box 1)
- "The Rau Plow Model Collection At Cornell University and the Evolution of Plow Design: A Lecture by Gerald E. Rehkugler," CAPE lecture, 2011; DVD-730 (Box 1)
- "Small is Still Beautiful: Establishing a Micro-Economics Agenda for Agribusiness Development in Africa," CAPE lecture by Ralph D. Christy, 2011; DVD-732 (Box 1)
- "Cornell Apple Breeding: Creating the Apples of the Future," CAPE lecture by Susan K. Brown, 2011; DVD-731 (Box 1)
- Simon Bauer 100th Birthday Celebration, 2011; DVD-795 (Box 1)
- "A Conversation with Royse P. Murphy," interview by Donald R. Viands, 2011; DVD-794 (Box 1)
- "Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statements, 1868-2009", CD-1395 (Box 1)
- "Cornell University Faculty Minutes, 1868-2010", DVD-733 (Box 1)
- William Barlow Ware: A Service of Thanksgiving, 2012-02-05; DVD-789 (Box 1)
- A Celebration of the Life of Barlow Ware, 2012; DVD-790 (Box 1)
- "A Conversation with Francis J. DiSalvo, interview by Abrua, Hctor D., 2012 (Box 1)
- "The Cornell-Nanking Story," by Harry Houser Love and John Henry Reiser (originally published 1963), 2012 (Box 1)
- Frank H. T. Rhodes Salutes Roald Hoffmann on His 75th Birthday, 2012; DVD-797 (Box 1)
- Brutsaert Parlange Symposium, May 14-15 2012 (book), 2012-05-14-2012-05-15 (Box 1)
- "Chaos, Levitation and Sculpture: Overlapping Circles of Creativity," Francis Moon, 2012; DVD-837 (Box 1)
- "Mind and Memory: Explorations of Creativity in the Arts and Sciences," originally presented in James McConkey's Course, March 4, 1996, 2012 (Box 1)
- Dr. John M. King describes the display of Antique Veterinary Instruments, 2012-05-21; DVD-836 (Box 1)
- "Robert Coleman Richardson, June 26, 1937-February 19, 2013," (CD), 2013; DVD-927 (Box 1)
- Memorial Photo Album: Robert C. Richardson, Sage Chapel, Cornell University, 2013-07-13 (Box 1)
- A Conversation with Francis J DiSalvo, 2012; DVD-793 (Box 1)
- A Conversatio nwith Richard P. Korf, Interviewed by Milton Zaitlin, 2012-02-17; DVD-791 (Box 1)
- Corson Manuscripts, 2009-09-10; CD-1516 (Box 1)
- Jack H. Freed, Interviewed by Brian Crane, 2012-11-13; DVD-862 (Box 1)
- A Conversation with Malden C. Nesheim, Interviewed by Norman R. Scott, 2012-10-27; DVD-861 (Box 1)
- Brutsaert-Parlange Symposium Photo Album, 2012-09-05; CD-1681 (Box 1)
- IASS-IACM QuickTime Videos, 2008-12-15; DVD-486 (Box 1)
- IASS-IACM QuickTime Videos, 2008-12-16; DVD-487 (Box 1)
- William T. Keeton House Grand Opening, 2008-09-26; DVD-485 (Box 1)
- William T. Keeton House Grand Opening and Dedication: Courtyard and Dining Room Program, 2008-09-26; DVD-484 (Box 1)
- Daniel G. Sisler and David L. Call: Recollections of Two Friends, 2012-12-08; DVD-926 (Box 1)
- Madison Wright and Tom Scott Reminisce About Their Experiences in Agronomy at Cornell University, 2013-06-20; DVD-925 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 1 of 10 [Abrams, Bauer, Bethe, Brutsaert/Parlange Symposium, 2012-09-01; DVD-812 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 2 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-813 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 3 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-814 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 4 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-815 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 5 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-816 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 6 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-817 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 7 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-818 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 8 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-819 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 9 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-820 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (A-B) 10 of 10, 2012-09-01; DVD-821 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (C-I) CALS Alumni Awards [2011], IASS-IACM Conference [2008] 1 of 6, 2012-09-01; DVD-822 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (C-I) 2 of 6, 2012-09-01; DVD-823 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (C-I) 3 of 6, 2012-09-01; DVD-824 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (C-I) 4 of 6, 2012-09-01; DVD-825 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (C-I) 5 of 6, 2012-09-01; DVD-826 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (C-I) 6 of 6, 2012-09-01; DVD-827 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) Janus Symposium 1 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-828 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) 2 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-829 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) 3 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-830 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) 4 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-831 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) 5 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-832 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) 6 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-833 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) 7 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-834 (Box 1)
- IFUP Streaming Video (J-Z) 8 of 8, 2012-09-01; DVD-835 (Box 1)
- "Analytical Elements of Mechanics, Volume 1," by Thomas R. Kane, 2005 (Box 2)
- "Analytical Elements of Mechanics, Volume 2," by Thomas R. Kane, 2005 (Box 2)
- "Spacecraft Dynamics," by Thomas R. Kane, Peter W. Likins, and David A. Levinson, 2005 (Box 2)
- "Compendium of Scottish Silver, Volume 1," by Rodney R. Dietert and Janice M. Dietert, 2006 (Box 2)
- "Compendium of Scottish Silver, Volume 2," by Rodney R. Dietert and Janice M. Dietert, 2006 (Box 2)
- "Enrico Fermi: The Master Scientist," by Jay Orear and others, 2004 (Box 2)
- "Knowledge, Perception, and Memory," by Carl Ginet, 2004 (Box 2)
- "Highlights in Dairy Cattle Reproduction in the Last 100 Years," by Robert H. Foote, 2005 (Box 2)
- "New Concepts of Cattle Growth," by Roy T. Berg and Rex M. Butterfield, 2005 (Box 2)
- "McGraw-Hill Series in Mechanical Engineering," by Thomas R. Kane and David A. Levinson, 2005 (Box 2)
- "More Other Homes and Garbage: Designs for Self-Sufficient Living," by Jim Leckie, Gil Masters, Harry Whitehouse, and Lily Young, 2005 (Box 2)
- "Advocacy and Interventions: Readings in Communication and Development," by Royal D. Colle, 2007 (Box 2)
- Publication and University event materials on CD, 2005 (Box 2)